Inventory of the Medicine Bow National Forest (Wyo.) records, 1897-1987
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Medicine Bow National Forest (Wyo.) records
1897-1987
Medicine Bow National Forest (Wyo.)
03654
22.73 cubic ft. (42 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Contains records documenting the history of the Medicine Bow National Forest in Wyoming.
History of Medicine Bow National Forest
The Medicine Bow National Forest (MBNF) of southeastern Wyoming was created in 1902.
Scope and Content
Collection contains correspondence, reports, newspaper clippings, maps, blueprints, photographs, and news releases on a variety of issues pertinent to the Medicine Bow National Forest including the installment of telephone lines, fire control, general administrative affairs, place names of land within the MBNF, grazing, mineral and timber rights within the MBNF, watersheds, wildlife management, and recreational activities. Collection also contains biographical information on Forest Service employees who were employed at the MBNF (1912-1958) and biographical information on early residents of Albany and Carbon counties and Laramie, Wyoming (1921- 1952). There are also maps of the MBNF; newspapers clippings; and photographs of ranger districts, campgrounds, timber cutting and Forest Service employees.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Medicine Bow National Forest at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from the Medicine Bow National Forest Office.
Access Terms
Camp sites, facilities, etc. -- Wyoming.; Forest reserves -- Wyoming.; Grazing -- Wyoming.; Forest rangers -- Wyoming.; Lumber trade -- Wyoming.; Mines and mineral resources -- Wyoming.; Watersheds -- Wyoming.; Wildlife management -- Wyoming.; Forest fires -- Prevention and control.; Pole Mountain (Wyo.); Medicine Bow National Forest (Wyo.); Laramie (Wyo.); Albany County (Wyo.) -- Genealogy.; Carbon County (Wyo.) -- Genealogy.; Wyoming -- History -- 1890-1918.; Wyoming -- History -- 1919-1945; Wyoming -- History -- 1946-; Blueprints; Maps; Photograph albums; Photographs; Scrapbooks
Agriculture and Natural Resources; Environment and Conservation; Logging; Politics, Government, and Law; Wyoming
Container List
- Series I. Personnel and People Associated with the MBNF, 1906-1978
  - Sub-series 1. Biographical Data of MBNF Employees, 1912-1958
    Contains short biographical accounts, newspaper articles, and correspondence documenting MBNF personnel. Some folders contain a photograph.
    - Averill, Clarence C., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Beevins, N.G., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bunnell, E. Mck. (Diary), 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Brown, Gordon, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chapman, Lewis Carl, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Clark, Donald E., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Clarke, R.L, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Clapp, Earle H., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Coughlin, Louis E., 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dunmire, M.V., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Duthie, George A., 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Fisher, W.H., undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Ginter, Paul L., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Granger, Christopher M., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Heaton, Phillip, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Helmick, K.J., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hennessy, Thomas P., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Henson, Hazel Wilson, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Hilton, Hubert C., 1934-1951 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Hughes, H.R., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Jeffers, D.S., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Jensen, Joseph E., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Lang, George, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Lindsley, Lorraine, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Metcalf, Walter, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Lovejoy, P.S., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Miller, Fred J., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Mullison, John H., 1923-1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Nelson, Jesse W., 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Paxton, P.J., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Pierce, Earl S., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Ratliffe, Mark J., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Rice, Ben, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Riggs, Richard, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Smith, Clinton G., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Stults, Hal L., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Torgney, Bruce, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Williams, Evan J., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Woodman, Herbert B., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Wright, Edward, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Sub-series 2. Historical Data from/about Individuals Associated with MBNF, 1921-1952
    Contains information in the form of newspaper articles, correspondence, and written accounts on people associated with the MBNF, such as residents and land owners, relatives, and people who worked in the MBNF.
    - Allen, Fred P. (Biographical Resumes or Notes), 1926 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Anderson, C.J. (Buck),(Biographical Resumes or Notes), 1923-1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Baker, Jim, (Biographical Resumes or Notes), 1923-1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bellamy, Charles (Newspaper Clipping), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bellamy, Mary Godat (Newspaper Clipping), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bengough, C.S. (Newspaper Clipping), 1934 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Boyer, J. St. A. (Newspaper Clipping), 1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Brewer, J.C., 1934 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Carlin, Vic, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Casteel, S.J., 1932 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chaplin, William E., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Comly, Willett A., 1934 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Cordiner, A.H. (Dad), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Cosby, Charlie, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Crout, D.F., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cummins, John, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Dickinson, William H., 1926 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Earnest, Boney, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Fee, Jack, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Foster, George, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Garrison, W.H., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Gramm, Otto, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Groesbeck, H.V.S., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Happy Jack, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Harnden, E.A., 1922 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Harris, Phillip T., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Heagney, John F., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Herman, Fred, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Hodge, J.M., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Hopkins, Robert H., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Hughes, John P., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Hunton, John, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Huston, Al, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Ivinson, Edward, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Johnson, Al, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Johnson, Nate, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Johnson, Sam W., undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Lathrop, George, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Lovejoy, Elmer, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Link, Wallis, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - McBroom, Ed, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - McIntosh, Robert, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Merritt, King, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Micheals, Howard, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Miller, Fred J., 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Mountford, Al, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Nelson, Osea, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Nichols, Kels P., 1929 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Payne, T. John, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Parrotte, George, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Peck, L.D., 1931 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Pennock, Taylor, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Pollock, Robert H., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Rathje, William, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Reader, A.R., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Reed, William H., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Rhinesmith, ME., 1934 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Rice, Anna, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Rivera, Ruby, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Shores, C.W., 1927-1934 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Smalley, Edwin J., undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Smith, Frank, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Sublette, John, 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Sundby, G.E., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Root, Chauncey, 1926-1938 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Taylor, MR., 1931 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Tilton, William Erastus, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Watkins, Jack, 1927-1934 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Webb, John, 1923-1934 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Willardson, James, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Wilt, Daniel M., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Woods, Sam, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Wymore, A.J., 1930 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Young, C.C., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Sub-series 3. General Personnel Information, 1906-1978
    Contains lists and directories of MBNF employees as well as information on personnel and people associated with the MBNF.
    - Address Books, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Biographical Information - Other Wyomingites, 1928-1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Coughlin, Louis E., Awards, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - List of Forest Supervisors with Short Biographies of Each, 1906-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - National Forest Organizational Directory, Wyoming, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - New Personnel [Short Biographical Resumes], circa 1976 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Notebook Listing Persons Employed by the Forest Service in the Medicine Bow Region, 1951 (Box 12)
    - Personnel Cards/Records, 1906-1931 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Personnel Report and Personnel History, 1906-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Reports on Local Residents' Opinions and Dealings with the Forest Service [Collection compiled by Louis E. Coughlin], 1909-1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Telephone List, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Series II. Administrative History Records, 1897-1982
  Contains reports, correspondence, memoranda, news clippings and news releases on a variety of issues, topics, and locations of MBNF. Information on financials, personnel, and other administrative operations can also be found in this series. There are also maps, a field journal, and a run of the MBNF's weekly newsletter (1975-1978).
  - Buildings (7310), 1968 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Charts, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Cora Grant/Berlin Mining Corp., 1966-1969 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Crow Creek Maps, 1900-1910 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Development and Control Programs (2650), 1941-1965 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Developments and Improvements, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Echo Lodge Evaluation, 1980 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Field Book [Journal], 1951 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Field Inventory- Evaluation of Fishing Waters, 1959-1960 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Filing System Handbook (2), 1970 (Box 12)
  - Fire Behavior Training School Materials [Manuals], 1957-1961 (Box 32, Folder 10-12)
  - Fire Behavior Training School Materials [Manuals], 1957-1970 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
  - Fire Control- Letters, Memoranda, and Newspaper Clippings, 1932-1958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fire Control- Reports, 1939-1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fire Control- Maps, Tables, and Other Materials, 1938-1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Forest Service- Fiscal, Financial, 1906-1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Forest Service- National Concerns, 1907-1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Geographical Place Names- Other Materials, 1926-1933 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Geographical Place Names- Letters, 1908-1951 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Grazing- Annual Grazing and Other Reports, 1929-1951 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Grazing- News Articles and Other Materials, 1906-1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Grazing- Permits and Other Information, 1915-1927 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Grazing- Reports, 1907-1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Hayden National Forest, 1910-1925 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hayden National Forest, circa 1921 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Historical Accounts and Reports, 1915-1952 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hot Shot Placer, 1967-1974 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - I and E Analysis and Plans, 1968-1969 (Box 42, Folder 4-6)
  - Inspections, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Inspections, 1946-1973 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Inspection and Survey Reports, 1955-1969 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Land Classification, 1905-1960 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Land Ownership- Letters, 1907-1959 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Lands Within the Forest, 1924-1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Laramie and Vicinity, 1923-1951 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Maps, circa 1940 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Maps, circa 1956 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Maps, 1903-1926 (Box 39)
  - Maps, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Medicine Bow National Forest Weekly News Notes, August 4, 1975 - August 29, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 7-9)
  - Medicine Bow National Forest Weekly News Notes, September 6, 1977 - October, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 1-)
  - Minerals Management, 1921-1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Minerals and Geology (2800), 1978-1980 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Mining Claims, 1967-1977 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1908-1975 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous [Subject Files, Numbered], 1903-1937 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Notebook- History of the Cheyenne National Forest, undated (Box 11)
  - Notes, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Planning (1900), 1972 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Pole Mountain- Training Annex and Other Material, 1959-1961 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Pole Mountain and Other Materials, 1933-1970 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Pole Mountain and Other Materials, 1927-1972 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Pole Mountain District, 1931-1968 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Pole Mountain District, 1909-1963 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Pole Mountain District, National Christmas Tree, and Other Materials, 1929-1982 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Pole Mountain District- Paper and Report, 1945, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Pole Mountain Nursery, 1929-1939 (Box 12)
  - Press Release, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Project Files, 1947-1960 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Proposals, 1972-1975 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Range Management- Letters, 1908-1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Range Management- Other Materials, 1909-1927 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Reclamation, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Recreation, 1922-1960 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Medicine Bow and Miscellaneous, 1973-1980 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Misc., 1907-1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Misc., 1909-1950 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Misc., 1954, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Safety, 1923-1952 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sand Lake Road (Engineering Operations, Correspondence, and Estimates), 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 3-5)
  - Scrapbook (Xerox copy), 1927-1953 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Senate Bills, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Special Uses- Happy Jack Ski Area (2720), 1970-1981 (Box 41, Folder 4-9)
  - Statistical Reports and Project Work Inventories, circa 1950 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Telegraph/Telephone Lines, Correspondence, 1909-1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Telegraph/Telephone Lines, 1912-1937 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Timber Management- Letters and Memoranda, 1904-1961 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Timber Management- Newspaper Articles and Other Materials, 1902-1960 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Timber Management- Reports, 1906-1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Transportation, 1909-1953 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Transportation System- Snowy Range Highway/Road (7700), 1975-1982 (Box 41, Folder 11-14)
  - Trespass- Letters and Memoranda, 1908-1919 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Trespass- Reports and Other Materials, 1908-1950 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Watersheds, 1940-1951 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Weather and Climatological Data, 1936-1949 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Wildlife- Letters and Other Materials, 1917-1958 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Wildlife- Reports, 1897-1940 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Series III. Correspondence, 1908-1979
  Contains letters and memos to and from MBNF personnel on a variety of topics including homesteading, fires, recreation, and general administrative operations.
  - Collecting Historical Data [Area Residents- Letters], 1909-1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1923-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1919-1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1908-1935 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Memoranda [Wyoming in General], 1923-1955 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Forest Service Employees, 1922-1958 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Memoranda, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Series IV. Publications, 1924-1987
  Primarily contains newspaper clippings about MBNF issues and activities, but also includes MBNF publications such as pamphlets.
  - Experiment Station Publications, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - "Forest History" (Periodical), 1968 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1924-1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1931-1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1961-1962 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, December 16, 1964 - June 20, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1974-1976 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, December 31, 1974 - December 29, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, January 3, 1978 - September 29, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, September, 1978 - July, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, August 1979 - March 1980 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, April 1980 - July 1980 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, August 1980 - December 1980 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, January 1981 - September 1981 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, October 1984 - December 1985 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, February 1984 - September 1984 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, January 1986 - October 1986 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, October 1986 - June 1987 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, August 1987 - December 1987 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Wyoming in General, 1929-1961 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers, 1924-1967 (Box 11)
  - Pamphlets and Periodicals, 1926-1952 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets and Other Printed Material, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbooks of Clippings (Eight), 1921-1964 (Box 34-39)
- Series V. Photographs, 1907-1985
  - Sub-series 1. Photographs Organized by Number, 1907-1968
    This set of photographs is organized by a hierarchical filing structure created by the MBNF. It contains hundreds of photographs and negatives of the MBNF, including people and personnel; lumber and timber operations; recreational activities such as skiing, picnicking and fishing; plants and animals; and forest fire damage, equipment, and prevention.
    - Outline of Photo Organizational Structure, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Exhibits (1603), circa 1922 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Exhibits - Floats (1603.2), 1928-1961 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Contracts and Other - Historical Data (1650.1), 1900-1968 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
    - Range Management (2200), circa 1962 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Range Management - Administrative Studies - Exclosures (2211.1), 1923-1949 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Range Management - Administrative Studies - Transects (2211.3), circa 1953 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Range Management - Herbarium (2212), 1921-1949 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Range Management - Herbarium - Poisonous Plants (2212.3), undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Range Management - Management (2220), circa 1951 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, C and H (2221), 1921-1953 (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, C and H - Branding (2221.1), 1921-1922 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, C and H - Marketing (2221.6), 1926 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, C and H - Salting (2221.7), 1920-1925 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, C and H - Overgrazed Areas (2221.10), 1932-1952 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G (2222), 1914-1942 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Branding (2222.2), 1922 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Camps (2222.3), 1917-1931 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Docking (2222.6), 1964 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Driveways (2222.7), 1935-1949 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Herding (2222.9), 1939-1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Lambing (2222.10), undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Overgrazed Areas (2222.13), 1949 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Shearing (2222.15), 1922 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Range Management - Management - Handling Stock, S and G - Counting (2222.19), 1938-1945 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Range Management - Utilization (2223), circa 1949 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Range Management - Utilization - By Cattle (2223.1), 1935-1952 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Range Management - Utilization - By Sheep (2223.2), 1911-1949 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Range Management - Revegetation - Plowing and Seeding (2241.3), 1945-1949 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Range Management - Improvements - Fences (2243.2), 1938-1941 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Range Management - Improvements - Driveways (2243.5), 1917-1949 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Range Management - Improvements - Cattle Guards (2243.8), 1938 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Range Management - Improvements - Bridges (2243.11), 1933 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Range Management - Improvements - Sanitation (unnumbered), 1938 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Recreation Management - Developed Sites - Campgrounds (2330.1), 1933-1960 (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    - Recreation Management - Developed Sites - Picnic Grounds (2330.2), 1928-1961 (Box 14, Folder 17-18)
    - Recreation Management - Developed Sites - Organization Camps (2330.4), 1922-1956 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Recreation Management - Developed Sites - Camp Furniture (unnumbered), 1934-1938 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Recreation Management - Developed Sites - Resorts (2330.9), 1923-1938 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Recreation Management - Developed Sites - Roadside Rest Stops (2330.10), 1960 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Recreation Management - Developed Sites - Construction of Facilities (2330.12), 1933 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Recreation Management - Administration (2350), 1961 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Recreation Management - Types of Recreation Uses - Fishing (2351.4), 1939-1946 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Recreation Management - Types of Recreation Uses - Hiking (2351.5), 1923-1925 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Recreation Management - Types of Recreation Uses - Hunting (2351.6), undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Recreation Management - Types of Recreation Uses - Riding (2351.9), circa 1941 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Recreation Management - Types of Recreation Uses - Skiing (2351.10), undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Recreation Management - Types of Recreation Uses - Vandalism (2351.14), circa 1956 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Recreation Management - Types of Recreation Uses - Motoring (2351.17), 1927-1931 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Recreation Management - Scenic Attractions - Landscapes (2352.1), 1940 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Recreation Management - Scenic Attractions - Snow Scenes (2352.2), 1912-1945 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Recreation Management - Scenic Attractions - Historical Items (2352.5), 1914 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Recreation Management - Scenic Attractions - Glaciers (2352.7), 1916-1941 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Recreation Management - Scenic Attractions - Lakes (2352.9), 1920-1941 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Recreation Management - Scenic Attractions - Lakes (2352.9), 1920-1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Recreation Management - Scenic Attractions - Mountain Ranges (2352.12), undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Recreation Management - Scenic Attractions - Rock Formations (2352.14), 1916-1938 (Box 16, Folder 3)